# DIEGO FERREIRA FRONT-END DEVELOPER



## **Profile Summary**

With a Bachelor's degree in Information Systems and **5 years** of experience in the technology market, my focus as a software developer lies in creating front-end solutions for **web** and **mobile**. My expertise primarily revolves around utilizing technologies like **React**, **React Native**, **Javascript**, **Typescript**, **CSS**, **HTML**, and a variety of other tools and libraries.

In addition to writing code with **quality standards**, I always try to maintain its **readability**. I value constant communication and enjoy giving my opinion on everything from design proposals to backend integration contracts. I always seek to be involved in technical and business decisions. In general, I like to feel like an important part of all the projects I work on, and I see this as a way to stay motivated to always deliver the best possible results.

#### Hard-skills

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React.js
- React Native
- HTML / CSS
- Redux
- Testing (Jest, React Testing Library)
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- GraphQL
- Global State Management
- Styled Components
- UI Components Libraries
- Bundlers (Webpack, Vite)

### **Soft-skills**

- Strong Communication with the team
- · Always involved in decisions
- Self-awareness and self-learning
- Time management
- Emotional intelligence

## **Work Experience**

# Front-end Developer - Thoughtworks (Remote)

Jun 2021 - Present

- Led the development of scalable web apps for major brands using React and React Native
- Structured and developed a micro-frontend from scratch to production
- Ensured quality through automated tests and best practices
- Presented projects and facilitated agile ceremonies
- Implemented integration of applications with web socket, REST API, and GraphQL

### Front-end Developer - Plural Systems (Remote - Freelance)

Oct 2020 - May 2022

- Delivered multiple web and mobile solutions for diverse clients as a freelance developer
- Took lead responsibility for front-end development in most projects
- Utilized agile methodologies, collaborating with cross-functional teams
- Innovated unique web solutions such as a thermal image manipulation tool for medical diagnoses
- Led the end-to-end development of web and mobile projects from inception to production

## Front-end Developer - IVORY (On-site / Remote)

Sep 2019 - Jun 2021

- Built innovative React & React Native apps with a scalable architecture
- Conceptualized & integrated REST APIs for optimized user experience
- Led complex visual vehicle tracking solutions with Google Maps & API integration

#### **Education**

• Bachelor's degree in Information Systems - <u>PUC Minas</u>

Jan 2017 - Jun 2021

## Languages

Portuguese - Native speaker English - Advanced